Guide to the D.C. Poets against the War records MS2251
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
D.C. Poets Against the War records
2003-2008
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
McCombs, Judith
Roberts, Kim, 1961-
Browning, Sarah
Miller, E. Ethelbert
MS2251
3 Linear Feet
This collection contains correspondence, flyers,publications and other material relating the Poets against the War organization.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Sarah Browning, 07/17/2008 Acc# 2008.027
Biographical / Historical
In late January 2003, in response to an invitation to a symposium by Laura Bush to celebrate "Poetry and the American Voice," Sam Hamill declined, instead, he asked about 50 fellow poets to "reconstitute a Poets Against the War movement like the one organized to speak out against the war in Vietnam...to speak up for the conscience of our country and lend your names to our petition against this war" by submitting poems of protest that he would send to the White House.
By March 1, more than 13,000 poems had been reviewed and posted by 25 volunteer editors. Since then the organization has grown to include poets from other nations such as England, Australia, Turkey, Italy, France, Germany, India, Pakistan.
Take from the Poets Against the War website, http://www.poetsagainstthewar.org/
Arrangement
Without series, organized by folder as the material was donated.
Scope and Contents
This collection containes poetry, correspondence, flyers, buttons, clippings and other material relating to the Poets Against the War organization. Using poetry as a means of peaceful protest, this group reached out to thier community through events and workshops.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Protest movements; Poetry; McCombs, Judith; Roberts, Kim, 1961-; Browning, Sarah; Miller, E. Ethelbert
- DC Poets Against the War(PAW) website, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- DC PAW meetings, plans, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Poems Read at DC PAW oputdoor events, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- DC PAW sign up lists and contact information, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- DC PAW reading, 02/12/2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- DC PAW reading # 2, 03/04/2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Events, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Events, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Events, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Events, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Events, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Events, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- DC PAW press, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Media panel, 01/2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Martin Luther King library poetry exhibit, 01/2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cesar Chavez High Schoool, 06/2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Punto Vivo workshop, 50/2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Wilson High School panel, 10/2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Katrina fundraiser, 09/11/2005 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Whitman festival, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- DC PAW press, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Anthology, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Expanded Anthology, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Anthology 2:contact information, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Anthology 2nd edtion production, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Anthology: Poems from Lord Hutton, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Anthology marketing, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Anthology reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Anthology financial records, 2003-2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Anthologies bookstores, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Voices in Wartime, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Beltway Poetry Quarterly, 04/2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Mayor Arts Awards, 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Washington Spark, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Divide City, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Teaching for change, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Arlington Arts Center, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Youtew, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Marketing flyers, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Front+ Back Matter, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Poetry on display at Martin Luther King Library, 01/2004 (Flat box 3, Folder 1)